

Eugene Brevdo Staff Software Engineer Google Research











Biography

Eugene Brevdo is the Tech Lead/Manager of the Learned Systems group at Google Brain. His research interests span several interconnected areas:

- Software systems for training and deploying ML, Bandits, and RL models.
- Uncertainty, evolutionary strategies, and population-based training.
- Machine Learning applied to optimizing large software systems (databases, datacenter scheduling, caches, compilers like LLVM and XLA/TPU).

Eugene received his PhD in Electrical Engineering from Princeton University, where his advisers were Peter Ramadge and Ingrid Daubechies.

Education

PhD in Electrical Engineering, 2011 Princeton University

BSc in Electrical, Computer, and Systems Engineering, 2005 Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute

Experience



TLM of the Brain Learned Systems Team (2017 - now). Clients include Spanner, Compiler, and Cloud infrastructure teams.

- · Built smarter query optimizers, cache eviction algorithms, inlining and register allocation passes.
- Grew the Learned Systems team from 1 to 7 researchers and engineers.
- Aligned engagements between Brain, Technical Infrastructure, and Cloud orgs.
- · Set research direction for systems and ML engineers.



Senior Software Engineer

Google Brain

Oct 2015 - Mar 2017 · California

SWE on Brain Applied Machine Intelligence team.

- Core TensorFlow maintainer.
- Developed interfaces and support for sparse and sequential input, debugged graph control flow, implemented CPU and GPU kernels; whatever
- Founding SWE / API designer of TF Distributions (now <u>Tensorflow Probability</u>).



Software Engineer

Google Research

Apr 2014 – Sep 2015 · California

Hacked on DistBelief, helped opensource TensorFlow.



Software Engineer

Lifecode, Inc.

Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 · California

Built supervised learning ML pipelines for clinical diagnosis of rare diseases from NGS assays.



Senior Data Scientist

The Climate Corporation Mar 2013 - Mar 2014 · California

I worked on two teams:

- Computational Climatology: Statistical weather forecasting in the short-to-medium-term scale (2 weeks-2 years) using a combination of techniques from climatology, machine learning/statistics, and spatiotemporal signal processing.
- Computational Agronomy: Analyzed, assimilated, and reconciled remotely sensed weather and agricultural data. Built growth forecasts for corn, sorghum, soy, and winter wheat.

Research Intern

Siemens Corporate Research

May 2008 - Aug 2008 · Princeton, NJ

Focused on applications of Compressive Sensing to inverse problems in medical imaging.

- Developed CS-based estimator for Computational Tomography with Sinogram Occlusion.
- Developed a novel CS-based reconstruction technique for Ultrasound tomography.

Projects

MATLB Synchrosqueezing Toolbox

This toolbox implements several time-frequency and time-scale analysis methods, including the Forward/Inverse Discretized CWT, and CWT-based Synchrosqueezing.



Reverb

Reverb is an efficient and easy-to-use data storage and transport system designed for machine learning research. Reverb is primarily used as an experience replay system for distributed reinforcement learning algorithms but the system also supports multiple data structure representations such as FIFO, LIFO, and priority queues.



TF Agents

A reliable, scalable and easy to use TensorFlow library for Contextual Bandits and Reinforcement Learning.



MLGO

MLGO is a framework for integrating ML techniques systematically in LLVM. It replaces human-crafted optimization heuristics in LLVM with machine learned models.



TensorFlow

TensorFlow is an end-to-end open source platform for machine learning.



TensorFlow Probability

A library for probabilistic reasoning and statistical analysis.



Featured Publications

Mircea Trofin, Yundi Qian, Eugene Brevdo, Zinan Lin, Krzysztof Choromanski, David Li (2021). MLGO: a Machine Learning Guided Compiler Optimizations Framework. CoRR.



Albin Cassirer, Gabriel Barth-Maron, Eugene Brevdo, Sabela Ramos, Toby Boyd, Thibault Sottiaux, Manuel Kroiss (2021). Reverb: A Framework For Experience Replay. CoRR.



Yuan Yu, Martín Abadi, Paul Barham, Eugene Brevdo, Mike Burrows, Andy Davis, Jeff Dean, Sanjay Ghemawat, Tim Harley, Peter Hawkins, Michael Isard, Manjunath Kudlur, Rajat Monga, Derek Gordon Murray, Xiaoqiang Zheng (2018). Dynamic Control Flow in Large-Scale Machine Learning. CoRR.



Yuan Yu, Martín Abadi, Paul Barham, Eugene Brevdo, Mike Burrows, Andy Davis, Jeff Dean, Sanjay Ghemawat, Tim Harley, Peter Hawkins, Michael Isard, Manjunath Kudlur, Rajat Monga, Derek Gordon Murray, Xiaoqiang Zheng (2018). <u>Dynamic control</u>

flow in large-scale machine learning. Proceedings of the Thirteenth EuroSys Conference, EuroSys 2018, Porto, Portugal, April 23-26, 2018.

PDF Cite DOI

Ashish Vaswani, Samy Bengio, Eugene Brevdo, François Chollet, Aidan N. Gomez, Stephan Gouws, Llion Jones, Lukasz Kaiser, Nal Kalchbrenner, Niki Parmar, Ryan Sepassi, Noam Shazeer, Jakob Uszkoreit (2018). Tensor2Tensor for Neural Machine Translation. Proceedings of the 13th Conference of the Association for Machine Translation in the Americas, AMTA 2018, Boston, MA, USA, March 17-21, 2018 - Volume 1: Research Papers.

PDF Cite

Dustin Tran, Matthew D. Hoffman, Rif A. Saurous, Eugene Brevdo, Kevin Murphy, David M. Blei (2017). <u>Deep Probabilistic</u>

<u>Programming</u>. 5th International Conference on Learning Representations, ICLR 2017, Toulon, France, April 24-26, 2017, Conference Track Proceedings.

PDF Cite

∃ Joshua V. Dillon, Ian Langmore, Dustin Tran, Eugene Brevdo, Srinivas Vasudevan, Dave Moore, Brian Patton, Alex Alemi, Matthew D. Hoffman, Rif A. Saurous (2017). <u>TensorFlow Distributions</u>. *CoRR*.

PDF Cite

☐ Martín Abadi, Ashish Agarwal, Paul Barham, Eugene Brevdo, Zhifeng Chen, Craig Citro, Gregory S. Corrado, Andy Davis, Jeffrey Dean, Matthieu Devin, Sanjay Ghemawat, Ian J. Goodfellow, Andrew Harp, Geoffrey Irving, Michael Isard, Yangqing Jia, Rafal Józefowicz, Lukasz Kaiser, Manjunath Kudlur, Josh Levenberg, Dan Mané, Rajat Monga, Sherry Moore, Derek Gordon Murray, Chris Olah, Mike Schuster, Jonathon Shlens, Benoit Steiner, Ilya Sutskever, Kunal Talwar, Paul A. Tucker, Vincent Vanhoucke, Vijay Vasudevan, Fernanda B. Viégas, Oriol Vinyals, Pete Warden, Martin Wattenberg, Martin Wicke, Yuan Yu, Xiaoqiang Zheng (2016). TensorFlow: Large-Scale Machine Learning on Heterogeneous Distributed Systems. CoRR.

PDF Cite

Gaurav Thakur, Eugene Brevdo, Neven S. Fuckar, Hau-Tieng Wu (2013). <u>The Synchrosqueezing algorithm for time-varying spectral analysis: Robustness properties and new paleoclimate applications</u>. *Signal Process.*.

PDF Cite DOI

☐ Sina Jafarpour, Gungor Polatkan, Eugene Brevdo, Shannon M. Hughes, Andrei Brasoveanu, Ingrid Daubechies (2009). Stylistic analysis of paintings using wavelets and machine learning. 17th European Signal Processing Conference, EUSIPCO 2009, Glasgow, Scotland, UK, August 24-28, 2009.

PDF | Cite

Ella Hendriks, Igor J. Berezhnoy, Eugene Brevdo, Shannon M. Hughes, Ingrid Daubechies, Jia Li, Eric O. Postma, James Z. Wang (2008). Image processing for artist identification. *IEEE Signal Process. Mag.*.

PDF | Cite | DOI

Contact



ebrevdo@



Book an appointment

yablak@



Published with $\underline{\text{Wowchemy}}$ — the free, $\underline{\text{open source}}$ website builder that empowers creators.